Abdallah Ibrahim

Mobile: (+20) 1124093527

E-mail: abdallanasr505@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/M45CJ3J

Xing: https://www.xing.com/profile/Abdallah Ibrahim13/cv

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdallah-ibrahim-0a2b15156/

Portfolio: https://m45cj3j.github.io/Abdallahlbrahim.github.io/

Objective Overview:

I am offering 7 years of experience in the web developing field (Full Stack Backend Mainly), College graduate seeking a technical position. Extensive technical experience at NTI. Motivated, enthusiastic and committed to be an added value employee at my work.

Personal Data:

Name: Abdallah Nasreldin Abdelrahman Ibrahim

Date of Birth: August 14, 1994

Nationality: Egyptian

Interests: Traveling, playing tennis and Music

Work experience:

- I work as PHP Laravel developer For AIPT from Dec 2023 till now
- I work as PHP Laravel developer For RayaGate in Landsberger Allee
 56A 10249 Berlin, Deutschland from Mar 2023 till November 2023
- I work as PHP Laravel developer For JoSqual in Jordan from Feb 2023 till Mar 2023 Leaved because its way to manage its projects non-suitable for me.
- I work as PHP Laravel developer For Resultier in twins fall, Idaho USA
 from Apr 2022 till Dec 2022 Leaved due to layoff
- I worked as PHP Laravel developer as freelancer from Sep 2020 till Apr
 2022 Leaved it because of instability of monthly income and to gain
 more experience
- I worked as PHP developer for Euro assist form Jan 2019 till May 2019 and from Feb 2020 till Aug 2020 Leaved it due to its closing because of COVID-19 Developing the website of the company and managing its admin panel.
- I worked as Call center agent for Vodafone Egypt Sep 2016 till Oct
 2018

Internships:

I was a trainee for Ipda3 tech for 3 Month as a Web Developer. From Nov 2019 till Jan 2020, I could Build 2 project by Laravel 5.8 and API by postman.

Education:

- Academic Diploma in Artificial Intelligence from the faculty of high studies for statical studies at Cairo university sep 2024 till now
- Nano degree in angular framework from Udacity from Jul 2022 till Aug
 2022 Graduation Project: Ecommerce Cart and products show
- Diploma in internet of thing from information Technology Institute (ITI) (https://www.iti.gov.eg/) From Jan 2021 till May 2021 My Graduation Project was about public transportation. It got the third place between all graduation projects in Graduation.
- Diploma in web Development (full stack web development PHP &Laravel): from National Telecommunication Institute (NTI) (https://www.nti.sci.eg/) from May 2019 till October 2019: good grade Graduation Project: booking system we could by it book service and knows how many time it Duarte. could get the 1st place between all projects
- Bachelor of Business Administration Faculty of commerce. Cairo University, June 2016 – good grade

Technical Skills:

Based on my Technical experience:

- front end => Angular, Bootstrap
- Back end => PHP/Laravel and js /node.js
- Databases => MySQL and Mongo DB
- OS =>Linux (admin |), macOS
- Knowledge of API Architecture Rest and SOAP& XML
- CI/CD => Git & GitHub
- Familiar with Devops (AWS) & microservices & Agile methodology (ClickUp & twillo)
- Testing => TDD / PHP Unit
- Ability to deal with 3rd party API (including payment methods and gateways)
- Algorithms & data structure & Design pattern
- SOLID & OOP MOT
- (master of things platform) and Google Cloud platform Connecting sensor to platform using MQTT protocol
- ERD (entity relation diagram)

Soft Skills:

Based on my work experience & NTI & ITI and university life:

Showing Empathy

- Quick thinking & Problem solving
- Time management: gained from my pervious and current Work.
- Teamwork: gained from my social work within my study in the university.
- Work under stress: gained from my previous Work.
- Multitasks and developing myself continuously.

Special Training Courses:

ICDL course Russian cultural Center summer 2014
General English Course British council summer 2015
General German Course Goethe Institute winter 2018
Special Skills:

Linguistic skills:

- Arabic: Mother tongue.
- IELTS band 6.5 (academic).
- B1 certificate at German language (note 3)